Finding aid to the Distinguished Visitors Files CA.MS.00005
Smith College Archives
Distinguished Visitors Files
1850-1998
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.00005
3.542 linear feet (7 containers)
Contains correspondence, memorabilia, newspaper clippings, press releases and photographs about distinguished visitors to Smith College.
Biographical / Historical
The materials in this collection have been accumulated over the years from various sources in and outside the College.
Scope and Contents
The distinguished visitors files contain correspondence, memorabilia, newspaper clippings, press releases and photographs documenting the visits of distinguished persons to Smith College since its founding in 1871. The material ranges in date from 1848 to the present, with the bulk of the collection falling between 1888 and the present.
Arrangement
The files are arranged alphabetically by the last name of the visitor.
Related Material
Additional materials may also be found in the faculty biographical files, alumnae biographical files and published materials located in the Smith College Archives.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.
In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Smith College--Faculty.; Smith College--History--Sources.
- Guest books (4 files), 1889-1925 (Box 70)
- Visitor list, 1878-1945 (Box 70)
- Abbott, Katherine M., 1908 (Box 70)
- Abbott, Rev. Lyman, 1914-16 (Box 70)
- Adams, Ansel, 1953 (Box 70)
- Adams, Maude, 1899-1908 (Box 70)
- Addison, Adele, undated (Box 70)
- Allbutt, Sir Thomas Clifford, 1911 (Box 70)
- Allen, Charles N., 1900 (Box 70)
- Anderson, Marian (Box 70)
  General
  See also: 12.HD 1943-44 Anderson
- Angell, Sir Norman, 1940 (Box 70)
- Arnold, Matthew, 1883-86 (Box 70)
- Avery, Eunice, undated (Box 70)
- Baily, Liberty Hyde, 1929 (Box 70)
- Baker, Janet, 1972 (Box 70)
- Baker, Newton F., undated (Box 70)
- Bancroft, Anne, 1969 (Box 70)
- Bangs, John Kendrick, 1898 (Box 70)
- Barnabee, Henry Clay, undated (Box 70)
- Barr-Browne, (Rev.), undated (Box 70)
- Barrie, James Matthew, 1896 (Box 70)
- Barton, William Eleaser, 1923-24 (Box 70)
- Beecham, Sir Thomas, 1950-51 (Box 70)
- Bell, Alexander Graham, 1916 (Box 70)
- Bennett, William J., 1987 (Box 70)
- Benoyendra, Nath Sen, 1905 (Box 70)
- Bernhard, Sandra, 1986 (Box 70)
- Bismarck, Otto von, 1890 (Box 70)
- Brailsford, Henry Noel, 1929 (Box 70)
- Bridges, Robert, 1895 (Box 70)
- Brooks, Gwendolyn, 1985 (Box 70)
- Brooks, Phillips, undated (Box 70)
- Brownell, Samuel Miller, 1954 (Box 70)
- Bryce, James Viscount, 1907 (Box 70)
- Burgess, Thornton Waldo, 1925-30 (Box 70)
- Burnham, Mary A., undated (Box 70)
- Burroughs, John, undated (Box 70)
- Burton, Richard (Box 70)
  See: Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?
- Cable, George W., 1884-1933; 1971 (Box 70)
  - Photographs, 1893; undated (Box 70)
  - Publications, 1949; undated (Box 70)
- Cadman, Samuel Parkes, 1931 (Box 70)
- Cannon, Joseph Guiney, 1941 (Box 70)
- Carman Bliss, 1896 (Box 70)
- Carmichael, Stokely, 1966 (Box 70)
- Carmirelli, Pina, 1968 (Box 70)
- Carr, Edward Hallett, 1951 (Box 70)
- Carreno, Teresa, 1910 (Box 70)
- Carter, Jimmy, 1975 (Box 70)
- Chesterton, Gilbert K., undated (Box 71)
- Choate, Joseph H., 1917 (Box 71)
- Choate, Rufus, undated (Box 71)
- Clapp, Henry A., 1902 (Box 71)
- Clark, Francis Edward, 1912 (Box 71)
- Clemens, Samuel Longhorne (aka Mark Twain), 1889 (Box 71)
- Coburn, Charles, 1909 (Box 71)
- Colonetti, Gustavo, 1949 (Box 71)
- Cone, Helen G., 1988 (Box 71)
- Cooke, Rose Terry, 1888 (Box 71)
- Coolidge, Calvin and Grace (Goodhue), 1920-33 (Box 71)
- Coolidge, Calvin & Grace: Coolidge Memorial room, 1956 (Box 71)
- Courvoisier, Jaques, 1958 (Box 71)
- Curie, Eve, 1940 (Box 71)
- Dashwood, Elizabeth Monica (Box 71)
  See: Delafield E.M.
- Davis, Angela, 1997 (Box 71)
- Davis, Ossie, 1991 (Box 71)
- Davis, Richard Harding, undated (Box 71)
- Dee, Ruby, 1991 (Box 71)
- Deland, Margaretta Wade Campbell, undated (Box 71)
- Delafield, E.M., 1934 (Box 71)
- De los Angeles, Victoria, undated (Box 71)
- De Mille, Agnes, 1953-54 (Box 71)
- Depew, Chauncey, 1894 (Box 71)
- Dewey, John, 1910-11 (Box 71)
- Dimnet, Ernest, 1934? (Box 71)
- D'Istria, Dora (Box 71)
  See: Ghica, Princess Helene
- Dix, William S., 1978 (Box 71)
- Dodds, Harold W., undated (Box 71)
- Donnell, Annie Hamilton, 1910 (Box 71)
- Dorr, Julia Caroline Ripely, 1880 (Box 71)
- Drummond, Henry, 1893 (Box 71)
- Du Chaillu, Paul Belloni, 1895 (Box 71)
- Dumas, Alexandre, undated (Box 71)
- Duthoit, Capitaine Eugene, 1918 (Box 71)
- Earhart, Amelia, 1918 (Box 71)
- Edib, Halide, 1928 (Box 71)
- Eeden, Frederick van, 1909 (Box 71)
- Eliot, Charles William, 1919 (Box 71)
- Farrarm Geraldine, 1939 (Box 71)
- Fiedler, Arthur, undated (Box 71)
- Fields, James Thomas, 1879 (Box 71)
- Finley, John Huston, 1914 (Box 71)
- Fiske, John (Box 71)
  See: Green, Edmund Fisk
- Flagstad, Kirsten, 1938-39 (Box 71)
- Forbes-Robertson, Sir Johnston, 1906-15 (Box 71)
- Ford, Eleanor M., 1915 (Box 71)
- Frost, Robert, 1956-61 (Box 71)
- Fuller sisters, 1891-1914 (Box 71)
- Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1961 (Box 71)
- Garfield, Mrs. James Abrams, undated (Box 71)
- Garfield, James Rudolf, 1904 (Box 71)
- Garrison, Wendell Philips, 1892 (Box 71)
- Gates, Henry Lewis Jr., 1996 (Box 71)
- Gaynor, Jessie L., undated (Box 71)
- Ghica, Princess Helene, 1879 (Box 71)
- Gibson, Charles Dana, 1894 (Box 71)
- Gilchrist, Herbert A., 1894 (Box 71)
- Gilder, Richard Watson, 1888 (Box 71)
- Ginsburg, Ruth Bader, 1997 (Box 71)
- Granville-Barker, Harley, 1942 (Box 71)
- Greeley, Horace Missing: June 1999, 1850; 1861 (Box 71)
- Green, Edmund Fisk, 1886 (Box 71)
- Green, Samuel Swett, 1901 (Box 71)
- Gregory, Dick, 1968 (Box 71)
- Gregory, Lady, 1976; undated (Box 71)
- Grenfel, Wilfred, 1911; 1913 (Box 71)
- Grew, Joseph C., 1943 (Box 71)
- Griffis, William Elliot, 1913 (Box 71)
- Guilbert, Yvette, 1916-17 (Box 71)
- Guiney, Louise Imogen, 1922 (Box 71)
- Gulda, Friedrich, 1952 (Box 71)
- Hale, Edward Everett, 1875-99 (Box 72)
- Hale, Phillip, 1926 (Box 72)
- Hart, Albert Bushnell, 1916 (Box 72)
- Hayne, Paul Hamilton, 1883-88 (Box 72)
- Heifetz, Jascha, 1927-28 (Box 72)
- Henschel, George, 1906 (Box 72)
- Herrick, Myron Timothy, 1917 (Box 72)
- Higginson, Thomas Wentworth Storrow, 1884 (Box 72)
- Hitchcock, Edward, 1908 (Box 72)
- Hoover, Herbert, 1943 (Box 72)
- How, George F., 1988 (Box 72)
- Howe, Mrs. Julia Ward, 1911 (Box 72)
- Howells, William Dean, 1905 (Box 72)
- Housman, Laurence, 1931 (Box 72)
- Hubbell, Rose, 1910-11 (Box 72)
- Hughes, Charles Evans, 1917 (Box 72)
- Humphrey, Hubert H., 1964 (Box 72)
- Humphrey, Hubert: Photographs, 1964 (Box 72)
- Jacks, Lawrence Pearsall, 1931 (Box 72)
- Jackson, Helen Maria Hunt, 1879-80 (Box 72)
- James, Edmund Janes, 1911 (Box 72)
- James, George Wharton, undated (Box 72)
- James, Henry, 1905 (Box 72)
  - Photographs (3 files), 1905 (Box 72)
- Jefferson, Joseph, 1895-1902 (Box 72)
- Johnson, Rev. Nelson, 1997 (Box 72)
- Johnson, Thor, 1950-51 (Box 72)
- Keller, Helen, undated (Box 72)
- Kennedy, John Fitzgerald, 1958 (Box 72)
- King, Martin L., 1968 (Box 72)
- Kingston, Maxine Hong, 1989 (Box 72)
- Koch, Frederick H., 1932 (Box 72)
- Kossuth, Lajos, 1950 (Box 72)
- Kreisler, Fritz, 1928; 1942 (Box 72)
- Leacock, Stephen, 1941 (Box 72)
- Lee, Gerald Stanley, 1897-1917; 1976 (Box 72)
- Lerner, Max, 1944 (Box 72)
- Lewis, Charles, 1921 (Box 72)
- Lin, Yutang, 1937 (Box 72)
- Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1915 (Box 72)
- Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1879 (Box 72)
- Lovett, Rev. Sidney, undated (Box 72)
- Lothrop, Harriet Mulford Stone, undated (Box 72)
- MacCausland, Dr. Isabelle, 1928 (Box 73)
- MacKaye, Percy, 1917 (Box 73)
- MacManas, Seumas, 1915 (Box 73)
- McCutcheon, George Barr, 1913 (Box 73)
- McGovern, George, 1981 (Box 73)
- McKinley, William, 1996 (Box 73)
- Mabie, Hamilton Wright, 1900 (Box 73)
- Macauley, Dame Rose, 1941 (Box 73)
- Mansfield, Richard, 1891 (Box 73)
- Marlowe, Julia, 1894 (Box 73)
- Matthews, James Brander, 1898 (Box 73)
- Mead, Margaret, 1975 (Box 73)
- Menon, Lakshmi N., 1959 (Box 73)
- Menuhin, Yehundi, 1932-82 (Box 73)
- Meridith, George, 1878 (Box 73)
- Merrill, Selah, 1908 (Box 73)
- Miller, Cicinnatus Hiner, undated (Box 73)
- Miller, Joaquin, undated (Box 73)
- Mitchell, Silas Weir, 1887 (Box 73)
- Mitford, Algernon Bertram Freeman, 1871 (Box 73)
- Morrison, Toni, 1996 (Box 73)
- Muensterberg, Hugo, 1902 (Box 73)
- Nash, June, 1996 (Box 73)
- Nash, Odgen, undated (Box 73)
- Nasr, Seyyed Hossein, 1962 (Box 73)
- Newton, Alfred Edward, 1927 (Box 73)
- Niebuhr, Rev. H. Richard, 1958 (Box 73)
- Olds, George, undated (Box 73)
- Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1949 (Box 73)
- Paderewski, Ignance, 1893-96 (Box 73)
- Page, Thomas Nelson, 1898 (Box 73)
- Painter, Nell Irvin, 1996 (Box 73)
- Palmer, Alice Freeman, 1899 (Box 73)
- Palmer, Charles Ray, 1910 (Box 73)
- Parker, James Reid, undated (Box 73)
- Parker, Sir Gilbert, 1900 (Box 73)
- Parks, Rosa, undated (Box 73)
- Pavlowa, Anna, 1920 (Box 73)
- Peary, Robert E., 1919 (Box 73)
- Perkins, Frances, 1933-40 (Box 73)
- Perry, Bliss, 1913-21 (Box 73)
- Pershing, John J.: Smith College Relief Unit, 1920 (Box 73)
- Phelps, Elizabeth Stuart, 1888-1906 (Box 73)
- Poole, Ernest, 1924 (Box 73)
- Pryor, Roger Atkinson, 1911 (Box 73)
- Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1909-42 (Box 73)
- Ratcliffe, S. Kerkham, 1918-23 (Box 73)
- Repplier, Agnes, 1921 (Box 73)
- Richards, Laura E., undated (Box 73)
- Riddle, George, 1895 (Box 73)
- Rogers, William Penn Adair, 1927 (Box 73)
- Root, Elihu, 1915 (Box 73)
- Ross, George H., 1911 (Box 73)
- Rossi, Alice S., 1975 (Box 73)
- Royce, Josiah, 1895-1910 (Box 73)
- Sainte-Marie, Buffy, 1996 (Box 73)
- Sanchez, Sonia, 1998 (Box 73)
- Sarg, Tony Marionettes, 1923 (Box 73)
- Saltonstall, Leverett, 1945 (Box 73)
- Serkin, Rudolf, 1988 (Box 73)
- Seton-Thompson, Ernest, 190? (Box 73)
- Seymour, Charles, 1921 (Box 73)
- Seymour, Thomas Day, 1889 (Box 73)
- Shedlock, Marie L., 1916 (Box 73)
- Sidney, Margaret, 1897 (Box 73)
- Skinner, Cornelia Otis, undated (Box 73)
- Smith, F. Hopkinson, 1899 (Box 73)
- Sousa, John Philip, undated (Box 73)
- Soyinka, Wole, 1996 (Box 73)
- Speer, Robert Elliott, 1906 (Box 73)
- Spofford, Ainswoth Rand, 1901 (Box 73)
- Stedman, Edmund Clarence, 1880 (Box 73)
- Stein, Gertrude, 1935 (Box 73)
- Stodland, William Leavitt, undated (Box 73)
- Stuart, Ruth McEnery, 1898 (Box 73)
- Sunday, William Ashley, undated (Box 73)
- Swing, Raymond Gram, 1942 (Box 73)
- Szell, George, 1947 (Box 73)
- Taft, William Howard, 1914 (Box 73)
- Tangeman, Nell, undated (Box 73)
- Taylor, Elizabeth (Box 73)
- Terry, Ellen, 1910-11 (Box 73)
- Thomas, Martha Carey, 1907 (Box 73)
- Thompson, Dorothy, 1941 (Box 73)
- Tracy, Hugh, 1960 (Box 73)
- Tropp, Vladimir, 1988 (Box 73)
- Twain, Mark (Box 73)
  See: Clemens, Samuel L.
- U.S. Treasury, 1912 (Box 74)
- Van Dyke, Paul, undated (Box 74)
- Vetter, Noemi C., undated (Box 74)
- Wallace, George Corley, 1963 (Box 74)
- Wallace, Henry A., 1942-43 (Box 74)
- Walpole, Hugh, undated (Box 74)
- Warner, Charles Dudley, undated (Box 74)
- Warren, Robert Penn, 1963 (Box 74)
- Washington, Booker T., 1901-14 (Box 74)
- Wendell, Barrett, undated (Box 74)
- West, Cornel (Box 74)
  See: Gates, Henry Lewis Jr.
- Wharton, Edith Newbold, undated (Box 74)
- Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf? Warner Brother's film production (WAVW): Newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 74)
  - Newspaper clippings, May 1965- Aug 1965; 1966 (Box 74)
  - Newspaper clippings, Sep 1965-Jul 1966 (Box 74)
  - Alumnae Reaction, 1965 (Box 74)
  - Warner Brothers, 1965-55 (Box 74)
  - Contract, 1965 (Box 74)
  - Smith Location Filming, 1965 (Box 74)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 74)
  - The Warner Brothers Episode: Mr. Herbert N. Heston, 1965-66 (Box 74)
- Wiggins, Kate Douglas, 1892-1900 (Box 74)
- Whittier, John Greenleaf, undated (Box 74)
- Wilder, Thornton, 1955; 1975 (Box 74)
- Wilkie, Wendell L., 1943 (Box 74)
- Williams, Harrison, 1960 (Box 74)
- Williams, Jody, 1998 (Box 74)
- Wilkinson, Florence, undated (Box 74)
- Wilson, Woodrow, 1897-1913 (Box 74)
- Winter, William, 1880 (Box 74)
- Wister, Owen, undated (Box 74)
- Wolf, Gustav Art, 1938-44 (Box 74)
- Woolley, Mary Emma, 1910 (Box 74)
- Woolsey, Theodore Dwight, 1875 (Box 74)
- Worchester, Dr. Elwood, undated (Box 74)
- Wright, Carroll Davidson, 1897 (Box 74)
- Wright, Mabel Osgood, 1907 (Box 74)
- Wyche, Mimi, 1994-95 (Box 74)
- George W. Cable: His Life and Letters Lucy Cable Bikle, 1928 (Box Bk)
- The Grandissimes George W. Cable, 1907 (Box Bk)
- Old Creole Days George W. Cable, 1897 (Box Bk)
- Women Aloft Valerie Moolman, 1981 (Box Bk)
- Henry James matted photographs (Box 74.1)